Guide to the Peter Paul Kellogg papers, 1934-1964
Kellogg, Peter Paul papers, 1934-1964
Cornell University Library
Peter Paul Kellogg papers, 1934-1964
21-18-893
Peter Paul Kellogg, 1899-1975
13 cubic ft. Includes 245 phonograph records and five tape recordings.
Correspondence, manuscripts, photographs, audio recordings, clippings.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, reports, manuscripts of articles, photographs, clippings, notes, memoranda, and printed material relating to Kellogg's career in the Laboratory of Ornithology at Cornell University; the history of the Laboratory; the Albert R. Brand Bird Song Foundation; ornithological expeditions to central Africa, Manitoba, and elsewhere; and bird clubs.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE:
Professor of ornithology and biological acoustics, Cornell University. Peter Paul Kellogg was appointed assistant professor of ornithology at Cornell University in 1938 and professor of ornithology and biological acoustics in 1953.He studied bird sounds and the vocal apparatus of birds, and pioneered the recording and study of songs of wild birds.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION:
Correspondence, reports, manuscripts of articles, photographs, clippings, notes, memoranda, and printed material relating to Kellogg's career in the Laboratory of Ornithology at Cornell University; the history of the Laboratory; the Albert R. Brand Bird Song Foundation; ornithological expeditions to central Africa, Manitoba, and elsewhere; and bird clubs. Much of the correspondence is with other ornithologists, education and conservation groups, departments, institutions, record companies, film producers, and manufacturers of technical equipment concerning the procedures and problems of taping bird calls; correspondents include Arthur A. Allen, Albert R. Brand, Myles E. W. North, Paul Schwartz, Lyman K. Stuart, Gustav A. Swanson, and various members of the Laboratory. Also, 245 phonograph records of bird songs, some with handbooks; five recordings made at Professor Allen's retirement party (1950); and handwritten notes (22 pages, 1961) made by Professor Kellogg's wife, Byrl Jorgenson Kellogg, keying recordings in the Cornell Library of Natural Sounds to references made by Louis Agassiz Fuertes in six papers on tropical bird songs published (1913-1914) in BIRD LORE.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Allen, Arthur A. (Arthur Augustus), 1885-1964.; Brand, Albert R.; Kellogg, Byrl Jorgenson.; North, Myles E. W.; Schwartz, Paul.; Stuart, Lyman K.; Swanson, Gustav Adolph, 1910-; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University. Laboratory of Ornithology.
Titles:
Bird lore.
Subjects:
Birdsongs--Recording and reproducing.; Ornithology.; College teachers.; Ornithologists.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- A - recording, 1954-60 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence - recording, Allen, A.A., 1954-60 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- East African Expedition, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Recording, Allen, A.A., 1961-63 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Allen, A.A., 1949-50 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Birds recorded on Western Expedition - A.A.A., D.G.A., Mar. 12-May 25, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- A, 1943, 1945, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Departmental, 1954-59
- American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1958-60 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Applications for use of recorded material, 1962-64 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Applications for use of recorded material, 1956-62 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- American birds songs, etc. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- American Foundation for the Blind, 1951-54 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Recordings, 1957-62
- Atwood, Sanford S., 1963-64 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- American Ornotholigists' Union 78th meeting, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- American Ornithologists' Union, 1949-55 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- American Ornithologists' Union Symposium, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Moses Asch, Folkways Records, 1953-59 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Audio-Visual Committee, 1951-52 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Assistantship Applications, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- B - Departmental correspondence, 1958-62 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- B - Departmental correspondence, 1954-61 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- B - Recording, 1957-61 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- B - Recording, 1954-58 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- B - Departmental correspondence, 1946-59 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Bell Telephone Laboratories, 1948-49 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Bird Control Methods, 1955-62 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- "Birds", 1948-50 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Bird clubs, by-laws, etc., 1946-48 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Birds - collected and received, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Birds of Africa (singers) (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Barro Colorado Birds (listings), 1944-45 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Birds of Central New York (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Bird notes, 1953-54 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Bock incident, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Book Records Inc., correspondence, 1953-55 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Recording file: Boulton, Rudyerd, 1959-60 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Boyes, Ed, recording, 1950-60 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Borror, D.J., recording, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Albert R. Brand Foundation, 1940-54 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Albert R. Brand Foundation, 1933-42 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- re. Brand, 1934-58 (Box 1, Folder 41-45)
- British Broadcasting - Boswall. Campbell, 1960-61 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- British Broadcasting Co. - Boswall. Jeffery, 1956-60 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Bird's songs needed, list of (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Bird Songs: suggested equipment for recording (Box 2, Folder 4)
- The Blue Jay (Box 2, Folder 5)
- British Birds, Songs of (the record) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Laboratory of Ornithology or Department of Buildings and Grounds (Box 2, Folder 7)
- British Broadcasting Co., 1954-63 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Bucheu, Walter, 1953-60 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Bucheu, Walter, 1950-53 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- C - Departmental, 1960-62 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- C - Departmental correspondence, 1958-63 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- C - Recording, 1957-59 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- C - Departmental, 1956-58 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- C - Departmental, 1938-55 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- (Clippinger F.) University Press Correspondence - recording (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Ornithology Canary Island Expedition Account #2607 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Council, Laboratory of Ornithology, 1958-61 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Council, Laboratory of Ornithology (duplicate) (Box 2, Folder 19a)
- (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Recording - Cornell University Press, 1958-60 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Chapin - James - Oveeny (recordings) American Museum of Natural History, 1950-51 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- (Comstock) University Press, 1951-54 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Cornell Plantations, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Recording - CBS Radio - Fassett, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- CBS Radio (recordings), 1952-53 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Columbia Pictures, 1951-52 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Colleges of United States and Canada (Box 2, Folder 28)
- (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Cook Laboratories (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Cornell Trust for Ornithology (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Cornell University Press, 1953-58 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Cornell Press Comstock Publishing Company, 1951-52 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Cornell Bird Song Records (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Corn sounds - clipping (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Cartoons (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Churchill Expedition, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Cornell Plantation, 1961-63 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Cornell Plantation, 1963-65 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Clippings (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Radio - clippings for (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Clippings (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Clippings (recordings) (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Clippings, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Clippings, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Clippings - sound recordings (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Clippings, 1946-51 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Departmental correspondence - D, 1952-62 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Departmental memos, 1953-56 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Davis, L. Irby, 1957-64 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Recordings - Davis, L. Irby, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Darrah, M. Elizabeth (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Disney Productions, recording, 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- D - recording, 1954-59 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- E - Departmental correspondence, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Engagements completed, 1958-59 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Engagements completed, 1960-61 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Engagements completed, 1961-62 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Engagements completed, 1962-63 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- E - Departmental, 1953-59 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- empty (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Engagements, 1953-58 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Empire State F.M. School of the Air, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Everglades National Park check list (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Expeditions - sound recording, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Extension reports narrative (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Farm and Home Week, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Federation of New York State Bird Clubs, 1954-59 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Phonograph records: correspondence re making of (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Phonograph records of bird songs (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Fish and Wildlife Service (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Folkways Record - Moses Asch (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Fox Educational Films (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Expedition - Ferguson's Gulf (Box 3, Folder 27)
- F - Departmental, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- F - Departmental, 1943-60 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Recording - Frings, Hukert, 1954-58 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Frogs (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Fish, William R., 1957-62 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Fish, William R. recording file, 1954-58 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Fish, William R. - B. recording, 1945-53 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Departmental correspondence, 1959-61 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- G - recording, 1954-63 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- The Gnat Catcher, 1958-62 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- G - Departmental, 1954-59 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Gleenewall, Crawford (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Gunn, W.W.H. recording, 1951-62 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- H - Recording, 1960-63 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- H - Recording, 1952-61 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- H - Departmental, 1947-59 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Hadley, Walter C., 1961-62 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Hartshorne, Charles, 1951-62 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Haynes, N.M., 1959-60 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Haynes, N.M., 1960-62 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Haynes, N.M., Amplifier Corporation of America, 1953-56 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Recording, Haynes, N.M., Amplifier Corporation of America (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Haynes, N.M., Amplifier Corporation of America, 1957-58 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Haynes, N.M., 1953 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Amplifier Corporation, B. recording, 1951-52 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- How Animals Hear (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Regarding page announcements, record: Songs of Western Birds (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Highlands Biological Station; reports, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Hoyt, Sally, 1958-62 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Hutchinson, Calvin, 1961-63 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- C.M. Hutchinson Art Studios, 1955-59 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- High School Natural Science Program, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- How Animals Hear (sent 1961) (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Cornell's Agricultural Progress Days: March 21-23; Science Program: March 28-30, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Farm and Home Week, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- How Animals Hear, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- High School Natural Science Program, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Hutchinson photographs (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Field Guide to Western Birds (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Field Guide to Western Birds (II) (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Field Guide to Bird Songs (Box 4, Folder 28)
- I - Recording, 1952-61 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Insurance, Bruce M. Payne, 1957-61 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Bird recordings, account (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Insurance, 1938-52 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Inventory, 1944-52 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- K - Departmental correspondence, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- J - Departmental correspondence, 1960-61 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Departmental, 1953-59 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- P. James, 1954-62 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- K - Recording, 1949-63 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- K - Departmental, 1950-60 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Krocker, Russell (April-May), 1962 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Kessel, Brina, 1948-55 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Kansas University recordings, 1950-52 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Kellogg: in Saturday Evening Post and Redbook, Ampex; also letter to Kellogg from Mrs. Kellogg, 1952-56 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Kivett, Paul W. file: sound, 1960-61 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Knowles, Louis and Denis, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- L - Departmental, 1959-63 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- L - Departmental, 1959-61 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- L - Recording, 1954-59 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- L - Departmental, 1946-60 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Laboratory of Ornithology - blueprint (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Laboratory of Ornithology, 1962-64 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Council, Laboratory of Ornithology, 1959-64 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Laboratory of Ornithology, 1957-66 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Laboratory of Ornithology - newsletters (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Lanyon, Wesley E., 1955-60 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Labrador - P.P.K., 1953 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Linnaean Newsletter, 1958-63 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Loew's Incorporated (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Ms. - "Counting the Winter Birds" (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Ms. - "New proposal for presenting and distributing Natural History" (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Ms. - "Recording Sound in Nature" (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Map of Howland's Island: Game Management (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Life Zone Map of North America (Box 5, Folder 35)
- M - Departmental, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- M - Departmental correspondence, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- M - Recording, 1954-59 (Box 5, Folder 38)
- M - Departmental, 1957-59 (Box 5, Folder 39)
- M - Departmental, 1945-56 (Box 5, Folder 40)
- Mc - Departmental, 1946-56 (Box 5, Folder 41)
- McChesney, D.S., 1961-63 (Box 5, Folder 42)
- McChesney, D.S. recording, 1957, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 43)
- McChesney, D.S. recording file, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 44)
- McChesney, D.S. recording file, 1958-59 (Box 5, Folder 45)
- McChesney, D.S., 1954-58 (Box 5, Folder 46)
- Maico Electronic Inc., 1958-60 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Massachusetts Audubon Society, 1952-53 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Meigs, Robert, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Manuscripts (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
- Various manuscripts by Kellogg (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Songs of the Alder Flycatcher, March 31; ms. Kellogg and R.C. Stein, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Maps: mounting on cloth (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Montezuma Refugee (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Muzak Corporation, Transcription Division, 250 W. 54th St., N.Y. 19, N.Y., E. Guthrie Sales and Services, 1945-52 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- N - Departmental correspondence, 1960-63 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- N - Departmental, 1951, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- N.B.C., 1953-54 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- National Audubon Society, 1951-53 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Natural Areas Committee, 1952-63 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- National Science Foundation, 1959-63 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Natural Area, 1947-58 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Nightingale, recording 19 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- North, Myles E.W., 1960-64 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- North, Myles E.W., 1958-63 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- North, Myles E.W., 1958-59 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- North, Myles E.W., 1954-57 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- North, Myles E.W., 1953 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- North, Myles E.W. (rec. 8-19-19) (Box 6, Folder 24)
- News clipping and miscellaneous pamphlets (Box 6, Folder 25)
- O - Departmental, 1954-63 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Okefenokee Expedition, 1954-58 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Folder 1 - 1954
  - Folder 2 - 1954-58
- P - Recording, 1957-63 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Folder 1 - 1957-60
  - Folder 2 - 1962-63, n.d.
- P-Q Recording, 1954-57, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 29)
- P - Departmental, 1945-59, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 30)
- P - Departmental, 1959-62; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 31)
- Recording - Pass and Seymour, 1956-59 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - 1. 1956-59
  - 2. Index of 35mm. Slides from E. African Expedition, 1956, (slides borrowed by Ornithology Lab 2-7-66, not returned as of 3-76)
- Pettingill, O. Sewall, 1961-64, n.d.; (5 folders) (Box 6, Folder 33)
- P.P. Kellogg, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 34)
- Precision Film Lab., 1950-53 (Box 6, Folder 35)
- Presto Recording, 1948-50 (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Publications by members of ornithology staff, 1935-46, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Publication: Horner Report, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Q - Departmental, 1949-60 (Box 6, Folder 39)
- R - Departmental, 1960-64, n.d.; (5 folders) (Box 6, Folder 40)
- R - Departmental correspondence, 1959-60 (Box 6, Folder 41)
- R - Recording, 1954-59; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 42)
- R - Departmental, 1937-57; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 43)
- Radio, 1964; (5 folders) (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Read, Bayard., 1952-62 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- R - Recording
- R.C.A., 1951-55; (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 3)
- R.C.A., 1939-41 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Radio Electronics, 1961-62, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Newspaper clippings (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Illustrations and photographs (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Reynard, George B., 1956-60; (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Extension: reports, summaries, publications, 1945-48 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Research projects - Dr. Kellogg directing, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Report: Research at Cornell by the Vice-President for Research, 1957-58 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Extension Plans for Ornithology, 1947-51 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Reports from Ornithology - Annual Project Extension, 1934-54; (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 13)
- S - Departmental, 1959-63 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Departmental correspondence, 1959-61 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Sa-Ss Departmental, 1955-59 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- S - Departmental, 1946-60 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Saunders, Aretas A., 1954 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Scheetz, Mrs. Francis (Virginia), 1953-61 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Schwartz, Paul, 1960-61 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Schwartz, Paul, 1962-63 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Schwartz, Paul, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Schwartz, Paul, 1963, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Schwartz, Paul, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Schwartz, Paul - Caracas, Venezuela, 1953-56 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Schwartz, Paul - Caracas, Venezuela, 1957-59 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Screen Gems: Keane, 1950-51 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Sheehan, Robert R., 1952 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Sheldon, William G. - report, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Sibley, C.G., 1953 (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Skee, V.J. - Electronic Applications, Inc., 1954 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Skibo Productions, 1938-39 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Society of Motion Picture Engineers, 1936-38 (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Spanel, A.N. (editorials), 1957-61, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Spaulding, David T., 1964 (Box 7, Folder 35)
- Stein, Robert C., 1959 (Box 7, Folder 36-37)
- Stein, Robert C., 1951-58 (Box 7, Folder 38-41)
- Stillwell, Jerry E., Recording File, 1952-59 (Box 7, Folder 42-43)
- Stillwell, Jerry E., 1951-53 (Box 7, Folder 44-45)
- Stillwell, Jerry E., 1948-51 (Box 7, Folder 46-49)
- Stuart, Lyman K., 1956-64 (Box 7, Folder 50-51)
- Swanson, Gustaf A. - re laboratory, 1960-62 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Swanson, Gustaf A. - television project, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Swanson, Gustaf A., 1954-60 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Songs of Florida Birds, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Sapsucker Woods: A Story of Science and Philanthropy (Box 8, Folder 5)
- T - Departmental, 1961-63 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- T - Departmental correspondence, 1950, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- T - Recording, 1953-59 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- T - Departmental, 1951-59 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Tall, Joel - Recording, 1952-59 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Tall, Joel, 1949-63 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  Includes set of correspondence from Kellogg to Tall from Tall's daughter. Many sent from University of Miami, some form the Laboratory of Ornithology, mostly relating to audio and acoustics.
- Tall, Joel - Recording (Kellogg), 1950-62 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Taxes and Permits - Recording, 1951-52 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Tead, D.B. - Recording, 1952-53 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- 13th International Ornithology Congress, 1961-62 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- U - Departmental, 1952-61 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- University memo (mimeo), 1960 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- University notices, 1958-59 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- V - Departmental, 1958-64 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Voco. Inc., 1951-53 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Voices of African Birds, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- W - Departmental, 1955-64 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- W - Departmental, 1957-60 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- W - Departmental, 1946-59 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Walcott, Charles - Recording file, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Ward, Rodman, 1951, 1960-63 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Ward, William V. - Recording, 1960-64 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Ward, William V. - Recording file, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Ward, William V., 1950-59 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Western Electric - Kellogg, 1945-48 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Weeks, Carnes, 1959-62 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Weeks, Carnes - Pamphlets (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Weeks, Carnes, 1952-59 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Westrex Corp., 1952 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Woods, Leslie J., 1960 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- X-Y-Z - Departmental correspondence, 1953-61 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- I.Y. Yeagley, Henry L., 1947 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Ziegley, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Division Accoustical Research (DAR) at Rutgers University, 1944-45 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Appointments, assignments (Kellogg), 1930-42 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Fernow Hall - building details (Box 9, Folder 18)
- One partial copy of thesis of P.P. Kellogg, typed carbon copy with notes, ca. 1936. Handwritten notes by Byrl J. (Mrs. P.P.) Kellogg re L.A. Fuertes' articles on tropical birds in Bird Lore, 1913-14., 23 pages (Box 10)
- Early recordings, probably by Brand, 8 records (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Early recordings, probably by Brand, 6 records (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Early recordings, probably by Brand, 3 records (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Early recordings, probably by Brand, 3 records (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Early recordings, probably by Brand, 3 records (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Early recordings, probably by Brand, 2 records (Box 11, Folder 6)
- "The Songs of Wild Birds," Brand, 4 records (Box 11, Folder 7)
- "More Songs of Wild Birds," Brand, 2 records (Box 11, Folder 8)
- (Record of six species privately published by Cornell Laboratory), 1 record (Box 11, Folder 9)
- "Native Bird Songs," Victor 25765, ca. 1935; the first commercially published record from the Cornell Laboratory; thousands were sold but it was very hard to interest any publishers, so no royalties were given; a very rare record, 1 record (Box 11, Folder 10)
- "American Bird Songs," vol. 1 (black) (Cornell), 6 records (Box 11, Folder 11)
- "American Bird Songs," vol. 1 (red) (Cornell), 6 records (Box 11, Folder 12)
- "Songbirds of America" (Cornell), 1 record (Box 11, Folder 13)
- "Cornell Guide to Bird Songs," matching "A Field Guide to the Birds" by Roger Tory Peterson, 1 record (Box 11, Folder 14)
- "Songbirds of America in Color, Sound and Story" (Cornell), 1 record & text (Box 11, Folder 15)
- "Dawn in a Duck Blind" (Cornell), 1 record (Box 11, Folder 16)
- "Florida Bird Songs" (Cornell), 1 record (Box 11, Folder 17)
- "Western Bird Songs" (Cornell), 1 record (Box 11, Folder 18)
- "The Mockingbird Sings" (Cornell), 1 record (Box 11, Folder 19)
- "Music and Bird Songs" (Cornell), 1 record (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Test pressings, 9 records (Box 12, Folder 2)
- "Bird Songs East of the Rockies," Jerry and Norma Stillwell, 1 record (Box 12, Folder 3)
- "The Whippoorwill Sings," Jerry and Norma Stillwell, 1 record (Box 12, Folder 4)
- "The Mockingbird Sings," Jerry and Norma Stillwell, 1 record (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Hans Traber - "So Singen Unsere Vögel", 11 records (Box 12, Folder 11)
- "Vogelring Schmallplatten", 1 record (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Pierre Strinati, 1 record (Box 12, Folder 13)
- From Dr. Stranborn -, slightly chipped (1 missing)4 records (Box 12, Folder 14)
- "Songs of the Greenville Mockingbird", 1 record (Box 12, Folder 15)
- "Song of the Lyre Bird", (very rare) chipped 1 record (Box 12, Folder 16)
- "Karl Reich Avery; Bremen, Ger. -, 1 record slightly chipped, 1 duplicate (Box 13, Folder 1)
- "Dawn in Old World Garden," Beatrice Harrison -, 1 chipped 1 record & 1 duplicate (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Edward Avis - "Bird Calls" -, 1 chipped 2 records (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Charles Gorst - "Bird Calls" -, 1 chipped 1 record & 1 duplicate (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Philip S. Olt - "Crow Calling", 1 record (Box 13, Folder 5)
- "Zoo Voices" (Julian Huxley), 5 records (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Test pressings - frog voices, Parts 1-8, Birds; Parts 1A and 3A ("Sounds of North American Frogs"), 5 records (Box 13, Folder 7)